# Askar T. uulu

### **Software Engineer**

| phone: (773)-799-0076 | website: <u>www.askartalantbek.com</u> | email: <u>murutchan@gmail.com</u> | LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/askart</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

Front End Engineer with 3+ years of industry experience. Goal-oriented, results-driven with a strong commitment to detail-focused collaboration. Dedicated to building and optimizing user-focused websites. Committed to high standards of web design, user experience, and speed.

I believe my past experience in the banking industry as a personal banker will be helpful in designing and developing user-friendly and intuitive websites. I would love to be part of your team.

#### **SKILLS**

FRONTEND: React, Redux, JavaScript, ES6, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Bootstrap

BACKEND: MongoDB, NodeJS, ExpressJS, RESTful APIs

OTHER: Git, NPM, GitHub, Jira, Jenkins, VSCode, Postman, Stripe, Heroku, Webpack.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Fulltime employed at Peaksoft (Oct 2017-present).

#### **Frontend Engineer(Contractor-remote)**

Echo, Chicago, IL| May 2019-Present

- Developed and implemented highly-responsive components using React & Redux
- Optimized components and reduced pages loading time by 15%
- Collaborated with back-end team to maintain RestAPI rules and reduced HTTP requests
- Implemented client-side pagination and improved performance by 23%
- Increased unit test coverage by 25%
- Reviewed code and helped new team members
- Actively communicated and worked with offshore team
- Improved performance 20% by adding & using reselect (memoize redux selector), React.Memo, React.lazy & suspense, gzipping & compression
- Refactored class-based components to functional components using Hooks.

## Frontend Engineer (Contractor-remote)

Yurtah, New York, NY | Oct 2017-April 2019

- Developed reusable React components
- Managed application state with Redux, implemented Saga
- Worked with back-end team to implement business logic using Node.js, Express.js
- Helped to built dashboard to manage client data using Chart.is
- Developed search functionality and improved performance by 20% using pagination
- Collaborated with the design team to implement new UI features

#### **PERSONAL PROJECTS:**

- Developed a full-stack app for the startup business with React, Node Js, Express is, and MongoDB
- Integrated Stripe payment system with React and Node.
- Created a dashboard panel with user authentication, as well as CRUD operations with Axios on the frontend. (used bcrypt, jsonwebtoken, redux)

#### **EDUCATION**

- General Assembly Bootcamp | Apr 2017 Sep 2017
- Udacity Nanodegree program (online) Jan 2017
- National University of Kyrgyz Republic (bachelors in finance) | 2009-2013